gcsu.edu 2019-07-03

# Georgia College Privacy Statement | About Georgia College | Georgia College

Below is the Georgia College & State University’s (Georgia College) privacy and legal notice for both its website and for compliance with the European Union

General Data Protection Regulation (“EU GDPR”). The Office of University Communications facilities content created for GC websites by internal departments and offices. The [Office of Legal Affairs](http://www.gcsu.edu/node/503) is responsible for compliance with EU GDPR.

## Website

### What we collect and why

The Georgia College & State University (GC) collects information from individuals or entities when they access any GC website.  Information that is collected from this contact is the contactor’s IP address, date and time of the website access along with the web pages(s) visited.  In addition, GC may also collect any information that it receives from your web browser, including browser type and version, and operating system.  This information helps us understand aggregate uses of our site, track usage trends and improve our services.

### Cookies

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users’ web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user.  Our website uses persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users.

### Security

Our office is committed to ensuring the security of your information. We have put in place reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards designed to prevent unauthorized access to or use of the information collected online.

### Sharing your information

We will not share your information with third parties except:

  * as required by law;
  * as necessary to protect GC interests;
  * as necessary to further GC research efforts pursuant to approvals from appropriate data stewards and the [IRB](http://www.gcsu.edu/node/802); and/or
  * with service providers acting on our behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the data. 

### Links to other websites

This site may contain links to other websites not affiliated with the Institute. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of other sites for assurance that their practices safeguard your privacy.

### Legal Notice

Notwithstanding any language to the contrary, nothing contained herein constitutes nor is intended to constitute an offer, inducement, promise, or contract of any kind. The data contained herein is for informational purposes only and is not represented to be error free. Any links to non-Georgia College & State University information are provided as a courtesy. They are not intended to nor do they constitute an endorsement by the Georgia College of the linked materials.

### Copyright Infringement

Pursuant to 17 U.S.C. Sec. 512(c)(2), notice of claims of copyright infringement should be directed to the [Office of Legal Affairs](http://www.gcsu.edu/node/503). For additional copyright-related information, please send an email to [legal@gcsu.edu](mailto:legal@gcsu.edu?subject=Privacy%20Statement). 

* * *

## European Union General Data Protection Regulation (EU GDPR) Privacy Notice

### Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing of Personal Data

Georgia College is an institute of higher education involved in education, research, and community development.  In order for Georgia College to educate its students both in class and on-line, engage in world-class research, and provide community services, it is essential, necessary, and Georgia College has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and community programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention. Examples of data that Georgia College may need to collect in connection with the lawful bases are: name, email address, IP address, physical address or other location identifier, photos, as well as some sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.

For more information regarding the EU GDPR, please review Georgia College’s [EU General Data Protection Regulation Compliance Policy](http://www.gcsu.edu/sites/files/page-assets/node-2015/attachments/eu_general_data_protection_regulation_compliance_policy_draft_final.pdf).

In addition, Georgia College units may have their own EU GDPR-compliant Privacy Notice posted on their website.

Most of Georgia College’s collection and processing of personal data will fall under the following categories:

  1. Processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Georgia College or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, community programs.
  2. Processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract. This lawful basis pertains primarily but not exclusively to research contracts.
  3. Processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Georgia College is subject.
  4. The data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.  This lawful basis pertains primarily but not exclusively to the protection of research subjects, providing medical and mental health services.

There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.

### Types of Personal Data collected and why

Georgia College collects a variety of personal and sensitive data to meet one of its lawful bases, as referenced above. Most often the data is used for academic admissions, enrollment, educational programs, job hiring, provision of medical services, participation in research, development and community outreach. Data typically includes name, address, transcripts, work history, information for payroll, research subject information, medical and health information (for student health services, or travel), and donations. If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your personal data, please contact the [Office of Legal Affairs](http://www.gcsu.edu/node/503) at [legal@gcsu.edu](mailto:legal@gcsu.edu?subject=Privacy%20Statement).

If a data subject refuses to provide personal data that is required by Georgia

College in connection with one of Georgia College’s lawful bases to collect such personal data, such refusal may make it impossible for Georgia College to provide education, employment, research or other requested services.

### Where Georgia College gets Personal Data and Special Categories of Sensitive Personal Data

Georgia College receives personal data and special categories of sensitive personal data from multiple sources. Most often, Georgia College gets this data directly from the data subject or under the direction of the data subject who has provided it to a third party (for example, application for admission to Georgia College through use of the Common App).

### Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the EU GDPR

Individual data subjects covered by Georgia College’s [EU General Data Protection Regulation Compliance Policy](http://www.gcsu.edu/sites/files/page-assets/node-2015/attachments/eu_general_data_protection_regulation_compliance_policy_draft_final.pdf) will be afforded the following rights:

  * information about the controller collecting the data
  * the data protection officer contact information
  * the purposes and legal basis/legitimate interests of the data collection/processing
  * recipients of the personal data
  * if Georgia College intends to transfer personal data to another country or international organization
  * the period the personal data will be stored
  * the existence of the right to access, rectify incorrect data or erase personal data, restrict or object to processing, and the right to data portability
  * the existence of the right to withdraw consent at any time
  * the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (established in the EU)     why the personal data are required, and possible consequences of the failure to provide the data
  * the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling
  * if the collected data are going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected

**Note: Exercising of these rights is a guarantee to be afforded a process and not the guarantee of an outcome.**

Any data subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filling such request with the [Office of Legal Affairs](http://www.gcsu.edu/node/503) at [legal@gcsu.edu](mailto:legal@gcsu.edu?subject=Privacy%20Statement).

### Cookies

Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users’ web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user.  Our website uses persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users.

### Security of Personal Data

All personal data collected or processed by Georgia College under the scope of the FERPA (Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act) complies with the security controls and process requirements set forth in the [Georgia College FERPA Student Rights](http://www.gcsu.edu/node/721) declaration and [FERPA Student Rights Notification](http://www.gcsu.edu/node/1336).

We will not share your information with third parties except:

  * as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including  but not limited to, 
    * its legitimate interest,
    * contract compliance,
    * pursuant to consent provided by you
    * as required by law;
  * as necessary to protect Georgia College’s interests;
  * with service providers acting on our behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the data.

Georgia College is a unit of the Board of Regents of the University System of Georgia (the “BOR”), and data is shared with the BOR and its employees.

### Georgia Open Records Act

As a state university, Georgia College is subject to the provisions of the Georgia Open Records Act (ORA). Except for those records that are exempt from disclosure under the ORA, the ORA provides that all citizens are entitled to view the records of state agencies on request and to make copies for a fee. The ORA requires that Georgia College produce public documents within three business days. For more information on Georgia College’s ORA compliance, please visit the Open Records Act page on the Legal Affairs website. 

### Data Retention

Georgia College keeps the data it collects for the time periods specified in the University System of Georgia Records Retention

  * [Examples of Human Resources (Employment) Records Retention Schedules](https://www.usg.edu/records_management/schedules/930)
